Tessa Husemann

Mediator

15298 Kennedy Rd, Los Gatos, Ca 95032 tessahus@gmail.com, (650) 272 9145

Skills

Language Fluent (with Work Experience) in English, Spanish, German and French. **Mediation** Facilitative model, non-violent communication, excellent organizer.

Interpersonal People person. Natural listener and communicator. Skilled at creating meaningful

and lasting professional relationships. In a supervisory and teamwork role.

Project Management

Adaptability

Lived in many countries - fast learner, comfortable with new environments and

challenges.

Technical Proficiency Indesign, Photoshop, MS Office package.

Work Experience

Mediation

- * conflict consultant for various teams within Mozilla. Global facilitator for Mozilla's Inclusion&Diversity Program (2015)
- * facilitative mediator, mediated ~150 cases in Small Claims and Civil Harassment Court with the Santa Clara County Office of Human Relations (OHR) and SEEDS (Non-Profit in Alameda County) (2014 - present)
- * mentor and coach for new mediators for the Santa Clara OHR and SEEDS (2014 present)
- * community builder: organizer and host for several meet-ups of South Bay Mediators
- * member, the National Association for Mediation (ANM) in France and Lyon Facilitator's Guild (2014)
- * conflict resolution course designer, University of Lyon (2013-2014)
- * spokesperson and assistant to the President, PlanetMediation (non-profit) (2013)
- * participant, CMAP (Center of Mediation and Arbitration in Paris) mediation competition (2013)

Research

- * Master's thesis on civil court mediation programs in Europe, Australia, Brazil and California. Project and research trip funded by the German governmental foundation Studienstiftung. Talks in France. Study was supervised by the Program Director and AMÉLY, a non-profit mediation association in Lyon (2014)
- * Bachelor's Thesis on the interplay between gentrification processes and the settling of Roma communities in a neighborhood in Lyon. Talks in Lyon and Berlin (2012)
- * urban sustainability analyst for Certu-Cerema, the largest public research center on Urban and Social Studies in France. Responsible for awarding the "eco-neighborhood" certification to French municipalities (2011)
- * independent researcher (Schwarzkopf Foundation), analyzing the impact of immigration on the southern European border (2011)
- * comparative researcher (Charlie Chaplin Foundation), studying community building in Shrinking Cities (Rustbelt and Eastern German Cities) (2009-2010)

Education

M.S. Mediation and Private Law - University of Lyon, France (2012-2014)

In cooperation with AMÉLY. A practically oriented Master's program with theoretical grounding in psychology, sociology and law. Skill training with AMÉLY, as well as mediators from the organizational, medical, therapeutical and family field

Mediation Certificate Program (40 hour course) - Santa Clara, California (2013)

Non-Violent Communication Certificate - French Association for NVC (ACNV) (2012-2013)
Basic and advanced training in 3 modules

B.S. Urban and Social Studies - Technical University of Berlin, Germany (2008-2012)

Specialization on participatory processes for urban projects, community building through participatory budgets on a neighborhood level for Berlin, gentrification, group facilitation